A Guide to the Virginia History Federation Records, 1966-1977
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia History Federation Records, 1966-1977
The Library of Virginia
42919
6 cubic feet and 14 boxes
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donor information not available.
Historical Information
The Virginia History Federation was formed in 1968 by various historical societies in Virginia in an effort to coordinate and strengthen the efforts of these organizations in their presentation of Virginia history. The organization changed its name to Virginia History and Museums Federation in 1975.
Scope and Content
Records, 1966-1977, of the Virginia History Federation consisting of correspondence, meeting and seminar papers, organization papers, financial papers, publications, articles, lists, and miscellaneous papers. Records detail the creation and operation of the Virginia History Federation, its structure, and its finances.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I: Correspondence
II: Meetings, Seminars
III: Organization Papers
IV: Financial Papers
V: Publications
VI: Articles
VII: Lists
VIII: Miscellany
Contents List
- I: Correspondence, 1966-1977., Extent: 5 boxes. (Box 1-5)
  Correspondence, 1966-1977, concerns the creation and operation of the Virginia History Federation and consists mainly of letters to and from the organization's president, secretary, and treasurer. Correspondence also concerns membership within the organization, its meetings, and its seminars. It also contains correspondence of its transition into the Virginia History and Museum Federation. Also concerns historic sites, museums, and legislation concerning history and its presentation to the public. Also includes photocopy of an 1895 letter regarding railroad mileage for Norfolk and Western Railroad in Pocahontas, Virginia; and a 1903 letter from William E. Dodd regarding access to documents in the Virginia State Library.
  chronological
  - Correspondence, 1895, 1903, 1966. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, February-May 1967. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, August-September 1967. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, October 1967. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1-10 November 1967. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 11-20 November 1967. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 21-30 November 1967. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, December 1967. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, January 1968. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, February 1968. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, March 1968. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, April-May 1968. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, June 1968. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, July-August 1968. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, September 1968. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1-15 October 1968. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 16-31 October 1968. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1-15 November 1968. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 16-30 November 1968. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, December 1968. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, no date 1968. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1-20 January 1969. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 21-31 1968. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, February 1969. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, March 1969. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1-10 April 1969. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 11-20 April 1969. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 21-30 April 1969. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, May 1969. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, June 1969. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1-15 July 1969. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 16-31 July 1969. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, August 1969. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1-15 September 1969. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 16-30 September 1969. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1-10 October 1969. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 11-20 October 1969. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 21-31 October 1969. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1-15 November 1969. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 16-30 November 1969. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, December 1969. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, no date 1969. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, January-February 1970. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, March-April 1970. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, May 1970. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, June 1970. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1-20 July 1970. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 21 July-August 1970. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, September-October 1970. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, November-December 1970. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, no date 1970. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, January 1971. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, February 1971. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, March-April 1971. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, May-June 1971. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, July-August 1971. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, September-October 1971. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, November-December 1971. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, no date 1971. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, January-February 1972. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, March-June 1972. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, July-October 1972. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, November-December and no date 1972. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, January 1973. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, February 1973. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, March-May 1973. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, June 1973. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, July-October 1973. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1-15 November 1973. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 16-30 November 1973. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, December 1973. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, January 1974. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, February-March 1974. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, April 1974. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, May-June 1974. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, July-August 1974. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1-20 September 1974 (excluding 9 September). (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 9 September 1974. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 21-30 September 1974. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, October 1974 (excluding 17 October. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 17 October 1974. (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, November-December 1974 (excluding 29-30 September). (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 29-30 November 1974. (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, no date 1974. (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1-15 January 1975. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 16-31 January 1975. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1-15 February 1975. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 16 February-March 1975. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, April 1975. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, May 1975. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, June-July 1975. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, August 1975. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, September-December, no date 1975. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1976. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, July-December 1976. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, January-March 1977. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, April-August, no date 1977. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, no date. (Box 5, Folder 14)
- II: Meetings, Seminars, 1967-1977., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 5-6)
  Meetings, Seminars contains minutes and agendas for the Virginia History Federation's annual Spring and Fall meetings and its board meetings. Also contains agendas, flyers, brochures, and registration forms concerning its seminars on aspects of presenting history to the public.
  - Spring Conference, 11 March 1967 (Randolph-Macon College). (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Fall Conference, 18 November 1967 (University of Virginia). (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Spring Conference, 6 April 1968 (George Mason University). (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Fall Conference, 19 October 1968 (Hollins College). (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Spring Conference, 1-3 May 1969 (Natural Bridge) See also American Association of State and Local History Conference of Southern Historical Societies (box 13, folder 2). (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Fall Conference, 24-25 October 1969 (Fredericksburg) (including minutes). (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Spring Conference, 5-6 June 1970 (Winchester). (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Fall Meeting, 21 November 1970 (Richmond). (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Spring Meeting, 17 April 1971 (Richmond). (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Fall Meeting, 17 September 1971 (Richmond) (includes minutes, resolutions). (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Spring Meeting, 25 March 1972 (Sweetbrier) (includes minutes). (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Fall Meeting, 18 November 1972 (Richmond). (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fall Meeting, 19-20 October 1973 (Staunton) (includes registration, minutes). (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Spring Meeting, 31 March 1974 (includes registration). (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Fall Meeting, 11-12 October 1974 (Abingdon) (includes registration, minutes). (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Spring Meeting, 10 May 1975 (Richmond) (cancelled). (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Fall Meeting, 4 October 1975 (Richmond) (includes registration). (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Spring Meeting, 14-16 April 1977 (Lexington). (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Small Museum Exhibits Techniques Seminar, 14-16 February 1969 (Richmond--Valentine Museum). (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Historic Housekeeping Seminar, 7-8 April 1972 (Lorton--Gunston Hall). (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Exhibits Seminar, 4-6 May 1973 (Richmond--Valentine Museum). (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Seminar, 31 August 1971 (Richmond--Valentine Museum). (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1968. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1968. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1970. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1971. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1972. (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1973. (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1974. (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1975. (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1976. (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1977. (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1976, no date. (Box 6, Folder 29)
- III: Organization Papers, 1967-1975., Extent: 1 box. (Box 7)
  Organization Papers contains various drafts and final copies of the Virginia History Federation's constitutions, including votes on the reworking of the organization's constitution in 1975. Also includes reports, speeches, talks, articles and other papers concerning the purpose and programs of the Virginia History Federation.
  - Virginia Museum of Science and History, March-October 1967. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Draft constitutions for Virginia History Federation and constitutions for the Virginia History Federation, September-October 1967. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Draft constitution for new structure, 1974. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Constitution, 1975. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Votes on new constitution, 1975. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Organization documents, 1968. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Job descriptions, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Special report, 20 November 1974. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Grant information, 1974. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Position paper, 1974. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Questionnaires. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Speeches, talks, articles. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous papers. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- IV: Financial Papers, 1967-1977., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 7-10)
  Financial Papers includes financial accounts of the Virginia History Federation, dues paid to the Federation, receipts and paid bills, as well as other financial records.
  - Statements and papers, 1968. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Statements and papers, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Statements and papers, 1970. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Statements and papers, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Statements and papers, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Statements and papers, 1973. (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Statements and papers, 1974. (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Statements and papers, 1975. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Statements and papers, 1976. (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Statements and papers, 1977. (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Statements and papers, no date. (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Check stubs, 1971-1977. (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - State Corporation Commission papers, 1968, 1970-1977. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Tax records and papers, 1967-1971, 1975-1976, no date. (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - 1968 dues, 1968. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1969 dues, October-December 1968. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1969 dues, 1 January 1969. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1969 dues, 2-31 January 1969. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1969 dues, February-March 1969. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1969 dues, 1-20 April 1969. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1969 dues, 21-30 April 1969. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1969 dues, May-June 1969. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1969 dues, July-August 1969. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1969 dues, September-December 1969. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 1969 dues, no date. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 1970 dues, October 1969. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 1970 dues, November 1969. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 1970 dues, December 1969. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 1970 dues, 1-10 January 1970. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1970 dues, 12-14 January 1970. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1970 dues, 15-31 January 1970. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 1970 dues, February 1970. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 1970 dues, March-May 1970. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 1970 dues, June-October, no date 1970. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 1971 dues, December 1970. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 1971 dues, 1-28 January 1971. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 1971 dues, 29-30 January 1971. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 1971 dues, 1-5 February 1971. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 1971 dues, 8-9 February 1971. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 1971 dues, 11-28 February 1971. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - 1971 dues, March-June 1971. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - 1971 dues, July-December 1971. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - 1971 dues, no date 1971. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - 1972 dues, September-December 1971. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - 1972 dues, January-February 1972. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - 1972 dues, March-April 1972. (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - 1972 dues, May-June 1972. (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - 1972 dues, July-October, no date 1972. (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - 1973 dues, November-December 1972. (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - 1973 dues, January-10 March 1973. (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - 1973 dues, 20 March 1973. (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - 1973 dues, 27 March-December, no date 1973. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1974 dues, February-5 August 1974. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1974 dues, 6 August 1974. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1974 dues, 22 August-November, no date 1974. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1974 dues, January 1975. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1975 dues, December 1974. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 1975 dues, January-December 1975 (excluding 21-22 July). (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 1975 dues, 21 July 1975. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - 1975 dues, 22 July 1975. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - 1976 dues, January-December 1976. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - 1976 dues, no date. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Dues forms, no date. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Paid bills, 1967. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Paid bills, 1968. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Paid bills, 1969. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Paid bills, April-May 1970. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Paid bills, June 1970. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Paid bills, July-December 1970. (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Paid bills, 1971. (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Paid bills, 1972. (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Paid bills, 1973. (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Paid bills, 1974. (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Paid bills, 1975. (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Paid bills, 1976. (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Paid bills, 1977. (Box 10, Folder 25)
- V: Publications, 1968-1977., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 11-12)
  Publications contains copies of the Federation's journal, The Virginia Phoenix, 1968-1974, including drafts; and issues of its newsletters published under various titles, including Newsletter, Virginia Phoenix Gazette, and VHMF Newsletter.
  - Newsletter of the Virginia History Federation and Virginia Phoenix, 1968. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Phoenix, 1969. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Phoenix, 1970. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Phoenix, 1971. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Phoenix, 1972. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Phoenix, including drafts of articles 1973. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Phoenix drafts of articles, 1973. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Phoenix, 1974. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Phoenix drafts for volume 7, number 1, 1974. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Phoenix drafts for volume 7, number 2, 1974. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Phoenix design, no date. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Phoenix advertisement sheets, no date. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Newsletter, 1970. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Newsletter, 1971. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Newsletter, 1972. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Phoenix Gazette, 1973. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Phoenix Gazette, 1974. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Phoenix Gazette, 1975. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - VHMF Newsletter, 1976. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - VHMF Newsletter, 1977. (Box 12, Folder 3)
- VI: Articles, 1967-1976., Extent: 1. (Box 12)
  Articles contains press releases and clippings concerning the Virginia History Federation and its members. Series also contains press releases and clippings concerning other historical topics.
  Chronological
  - Articles, 1967. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Articles, 1968. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Articles, 1969. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Articles, 1970. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Articles, 1971. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Articles, 1972. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Articles, 1973. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Articles, 1975. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Articles, 1976. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Articles, no date. (Box 12, Folder 13)
- VII: Lists, 1967-1977., Extent: 1. (Box 12)
  Lists contains membership lists and dues paid lists for the Virginia History Federation and its journal.
  - Lists, 1967. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Lists, 1968. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Lists, 1969. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Lists, 1970. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Lists, 1971. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Lists, 1972. (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Lists, 1973. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Lists, 1974. (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Lists, 1975. (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Lists, 1976. (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Lists, 1977. (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Lists, no date. (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Virginia History Federation Directory of Historical Societies and History-oriented Organizations in Virginia. (Box 12, Folder 26)
- VIII: Miscellany., Extent: 1 box. (Box 13)
  Miscellany contains correspondence, journals and newsletters, forms and applications, minutes, brochures, reports, and ads from various historical societies, historic sites, and professional organizations in Virginia and the United States. Miscellany also includes legislation and resolutions passed by the United States House of Representatives and the Virginia House of Delegates. Also includes a research paper by Guy V. Cavallo on Arlington, Virginia, voting trends.
  - American Association for State and Local History. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - American Association for State and Local History Conference of Southern Historical Societies, 1-4 May 1969(Natural Bridge). See also Spring Conference, 1-3 May 1969 (box 6, folder 1). (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - American Bicentennial Commission newsletter and fact sheet, February 1971. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Augusta Historical Society. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Confederate Memorial Literary Society Award. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Federated Arts Council of Richmond, Inc., meeting, 29 May 1974. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Fort Monroe Casemate Museum publications, 1967, 1970, 1972. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Historical Society of Washington County, Virginia, Inc., newsletters, 1973-1974. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 10th International Congress of Genealogical and Heraldic Sciences, 1970. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - National American Studies Faculty Community Museums Programs. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - National Historical Publications and Records Commission. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - New York Bicentennial Commission newsletter The Correspondent, 1970-1971. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Norfolk Historical Society newsletters and bulletins, 1967-1968. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Pioneer America Society. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Repair and Restoration, Inc. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Independence Bicentennial Commission, 1970-1971. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Guy V. Cavallo research paper--Arlington Voting Trends, 1960-1972. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - United States House of Representatives legislation and resolutions, 1969, 1974. (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Virginia House of Delegates resolution, 1974. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Wolf Trap program, 1975. (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Rohm and Haas plexiglas. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Societies--Smyth County Historical and Museum Society Inc., Tennessee Association of Museums, and League of Historical Societies of New Jersey. (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Museum and historic sites brochures--Lynchburg Historical Museum and Red Hill Shrine. (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Newsletters--Notes on Virginia (Virginia Historic Landmarks Commission), Cultural Cross-Currents (Virginia Commission of the Arts and Humanities), Microforum (Microfilming Corporation of America), Prison Civil War Round Table Newsletter, and RCHA News (Regional Conference of Historical Agencies--New York). (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - 24th Annual Seminars on American Culture at Cooperstown (New York State Historical Association), Twenty-Ninth Conference in Early American History (Sleepy Hollow Restorations, Inc., and Institute of Early American History and Culture), Historical Resources: Finding, Preserving, Using (Woodrow Wilson Birthplace Foundation), Program Series for Educational Communication Association, and World Conference on Records and Genealogical Seminar. (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Manassas Heritage Lost (North South Trader), The Forms of Culture (Virginia Cultural Development Study Commission), and Guide to Effective Media Relations (SEMC Notes). (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Forms and applications. (Box 13, Folder 27)
- Oversize., Extent: 1 box. (Box 14)
  Oversize material from the collection.
  - Treasurer's account book, 1968-1971 (from box 7). (Box 14)
  - Financial statement, 6 August 1973 (from box 7 folder 19). (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Phoenix negative film, volume 5, number 2, 1972 (from box 11 folder 5). (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Phoenix layout, volume 6, numbers 1-2, 1973 (from box 11 folder 6). (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Wayside Inn-Quirer (from box 13 folder 23). (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Directory orders envelope, 1970. (Box 14, Folder 5)